wvi.org 2018-02-02

# Privacy Policy | World Vision International

## Your assurance of privacy 

## Thank you for wanting to make a difference.

World Vision International has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this site: [www.wvi.org](http://www.wvi.org/).

You do not have to provide any personal information on our Web site unless you choose to do so. Various locations within our Web site may invite you to give us certain contact information (e.g., name, address, telephone or fax numbers, e-mail address) and other demographic information (e.g., nationality) if you desire more information about our organisation. We may use this contact information to send you information about World Vision and its programmes. Your contact information may also be used to contact you when necessary. You may opt-out of receiving future communications by visiting the form again and submitting a request.

You may also provide personal information on our Web site if you wish to apply for employment at World Vision International or another member entity in the World Vision Partnership. World Vision International maintains a separate privacy statement, which can be found on this Web site when you click “Careers”, pertaining to such personal information.

World Vision International assures you that the identity of all who contact us through this Web site is kept confidential: we do not rent, sell, or exchange our mailing lists, or otherwise disclose such information to third parties, except as may be required by law, or through voluntary cooperation with law enforcement authorities if we judge that such cooperation is necessary to avoid potential serious harm. We may also provide your contact information to other member entities in the World Vision Partnership (e.g., the World Vision entity in your home country), which will handle the information in accordance with their own privacy policies.

As with most other Internet sites, our web servers utilise “cookies” to track a user’s activity within our site as well as record the IP address of each visitor to this site. A cookie is a small data file that is stored on your computer. A cookie contains a unique identifying feature that allows our computer to recognise you when you return to the World Vision site. The recorded IP address tells us which domain you visited from (for instance, aol.com), but not your email address or other private and personal information. We use the information we record to help diagnose problems with our servers, to administer this website more effectively, and to gather broad demographic information about what countries and domains our visitors hail from and their behavior on our site.

We may share aggregate statistical information (e.g., the number of visitors to our Web site), whether gathered by our Web servers or through submissions from visitors, with third parties. These statistics do not include personal information. 

World Vision International specifically uses Google Analytics and OpenTracker to gather statistical information about web traffic to WVI.org. Google Analytics is subject to the privacy policy of Google, Inc, which you can find on Google's website and OpenTracker is subject to the following privacy policy: <http://www.opentracker.net/content/privacy-statement>. These data are used to optimise our website for our visitors, and do not include personally identifiable information. 

This Web site may contain links to other sites, including links which frame the content of the other sites within the World Vision name and logo. World Vision International is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other Web sites, even if our name and logo are still on the top of the screen.

This privacy statement has been updated and is effective as of September 2016. World Vision International may make changes to this privacy statement from time to time. The revised statement will be effective immediately upon posting to our Web site. Please check the effective date of this privacy statement to determine whether changes have been made since the last time you visited this Web site.

### Contacting the Website

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this Web site, or your dealings with this Web site, please [Contact Us](http://www.wvi.org/contact-world-vision)
